

ZAFER CELALOĞLU TC.,20th March 1991 İstanbul/Turkey +90 538 449 98 78 zafer.celaloglu@gmail.com

#### **Career Summary**

Possess 3+ years of experience as an Android Developer with an extensive track record of developing and maintaining high-quality android applications for a range of corporate technology companies including telecommunication, e-commerce, customer electronics, consumer intelligence and engagement during my employment in a variety of companies including startups.

### **Experience**

## Android Developer Turkcell, Istanbul, Turkey

09.2019 -

Turkcell Iletisim Hizmetleri AS (Turkcell) is a converged communication and technology services player with regional assets and globally relevant services. The Company provides mobile and fixed voice, data, television, and other services over its network in Turkey.

• Working on Yaani browser app which is based on Mozilla Firefox Fenix open source project for developing new features.

## Android Developer Veloxity, Istanbul, Turkey

03.2019 - 08.2019

Veloxity, Inc. is a consumer intelligence and engagement company based in Silicon Valley. Its speciality is in behavioral analytics, more specifically understanding consumer behavior through analysis of mobile device data. Leveraging big data and artificial intelligence technologies. Veloxity decodes consumers' real-life habits and behaviors.

• Worked on SDK project which collecting out of app data related with networking, location,

device etc.

- Was responsible to convert background services in order to make them compatible with new android OS versions especially Oreo and above devices.
- Worked on legacy code by refactoring core features to make them more efficient and robust.

## Android Developer Monument Labs Inc., Istanbul, Turkey

06.2017 - 02.2019

Monument is a connected device that helps you to store, organize and view photos and videos with zero effort. It syncs your content from cameras and smartphones and provides a high-speed, private access to memories.

- Worked at international startup as a remote developer.(it is currently sold at more than 94 countries via Amazon, Bestbuy, B&H, Walmart retailers)
- Was one of the core developers for converting hybrid (written in React Native) app to Native one written in both Java, Kotlin programming languages.
- Played remarkable role in the process of designing and developing core features.
- Figured out lots of customer complaints and technical problems.

#### Android Developer Tmob Mobile Technology, Istanbul, Turkey

07.2016 - 06.2017

Tmob is a mobile technology powerhouse, driving growth and success to businesses and partners with its innovative SaaS, PaaS and premium solutions, since 2009. Its end-to-end solutions address and cover mobile business needs fully with an enhanced focus on performance.

- Involved in great projects from scratch such as Paycell which is a payment platform that keeps users' credit cards securely and allow them to shop on their instructions without having to share their cards at Paycell dealers.
- Worked on a couple of projects which belong to well-known corporate companies in the airline, banking, and telecommunication to maintain and develop new features.
- Leaded project of Tmob's own application called Tappz (is a tool creates a fully customizable native mobile application without a line of coding for companies that are working in e-commerce industry) to maintain and develop new features responsibility.

# Software Verification Engineer Netas, Istanbul, Turkey

07.2014 - 07.2015

Netas offers innovative and creative solutions in information and communication technologies including end- to-end value added solutions, system integration and technology services to providers and corporations in both local and international markets.

- Was responsible for preparing test documents and executing them.
- Worked on Wireshark (is a tool used to analyze network traffic), Putty (is a free and open-source terminal emulator, serial console and network file transfer application), WinSCP (for file transfer using secure FTP) tools.
- Contributed to development of Minitaf (test automation tool) written in Java to simulate both SIP and REST side.
- · Had experience with agile methodologies.
- Had experience with CI/CD tools especially on Jenkins.

#### **Education**

Bahcesehir University Software Engineering, B.Sc. Istanbul, Turkey 09.2009 - 06.2014

### Languages

- English Fluent
- Turkish Native